newislamicdirections.com 2009-05-27

# New Islamic Directions - Imam Zaid Shakir

Privacy

Protecting your privacy is important to New Islamic Directions. We strive to keep your personal information confidential. By ensuring that you are aware of and understand the New Islamic Directions Customer Privacy Policy, we can provide you with better service. Please take a moment to read the following policy to learn how we handle your personal information. 

**Why we collect personal information**   
New Islamic Directions collects and uses your personal information to give you superior customer service, to provide you with convenient access to our products and services, and to make a wider range available to you. In addition, we use your personal information to keep you up to date on the latest product announcements, new and events updates, special offers, and other information we think you would like to hear about. This may occasionally include information from other organizations about events and updates that are related to New Islamic Directions. From time to time, we may also use your personal information to contact you to participate in a market research survey, so that we can gauge customer satisfaction and develop better products. 

**How we collect personal information**   
We collect information about you in several ways. For example, we might ask for your contact information when you correspond with us, call us to make a purchase or request service, register to attend a seminar, or participate in an online survey. In addition, when you register a new NID product, or ask to be included in an email mailing list, we collect and store the information you provide in a secure database. 

To save you time and make our web services even easier to use, some areas of the NID website allow you to create an “NID ID” using your personal information. Here iss how it works: Simply fill out a brief profile with your name, phone number, and email address, then choose a password and password hint (such as the month and day of your birth) for security. The system saves your information and assigns you a personal NID ID. Next time you order something from the NID Store or register a new product, you can simply enter your NID ID and password thesystem will automatically look up the information it needs. 

**When we disclose personal information**   
If you check “I agree to the use of my personal data” the box during registration, NID will share you personal information with organizations it works with. 

**How we protect your personal information**   
NID safeguards the security of the data you send us with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. We urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet. Change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers, and make sure you use a secure browser. 

The NID Store uses industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption on all web pages where personal information is required. To make purchases from the NID Store, you must use an SSL-enabled browser such as Internet Explorer 6.0 or later, or FireFox. This protects the confidentiality of your personal and credit card information while it is transmitted over the Internet.   
**  
Access to your personal information**   
You always have access to the information we have about you. To review and update your personal contact information, simply click onMy account. If you would like to review other personal information that NID may have about you, email us at [info@newislamicdirections.com](mailto:info@newislamicdirections.com). 

**Collecting other personal information**   
When you browse New Islamic Directions website, you are able to do so anonymously. Generally, we don’t collect personal information when you browse not even your email address. Your browser, however, does automatically tell us the type of computer and operating system you are using. 

Like many websites, the New Islamic Directions website uses “cookie” technology. When you first connect to our site, the cookie identifies your browser with a unique, random number. The cookies we use do not reveal any personal information about you, except perhaps your first name so we can welcome you on your next visit. Cookies help us understand which parts of our websites are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how long they spend there. We use cookies to study traffic patterns on our site so we can make the site even better. 

In some of our email to you, we use a &qquot;click-through URL.” When you click one of these URLs, you pass through our web server before arriving at the website that is your destination. We track click-throughs to help us determine your interest in particular topics and measure the effectiveness of our customer communications. 

**Our commitment to privacy**   
To make sure your personal information remains confidential, we communicate these privacy guidelines to every New Islamic Directions employee. 

New Islamic Directions does not knowingly solicit personal information from children or send them requests for personal information. 

New Islamic Directions website contains links to other sites. NID does not share your personal information with those websites and is not responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to learn about the privacy policies of those companies. 

If we are going to use your personal information differently from that stated at the time of collection, we will try to contact you via email using the most recent information we have. If you have not given us permission to communicate with you, you will not be contacted, nor will we use your personal information in a new manner. 

The New Islamic Directions Customer Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time. We encourage you to review the privacy policy regularly for any changes.
